Girona, Spain

🔾 wilberquito | in wilberquito | 🏕 wilberquito.github.io | 🗗 typingwil@gmail.com | 🖂 (+34) 698-40-53-59

"The best way to predict the future is to create it."

#### About

With more than three years of experience in IT solutions, I began my career as a Software Developer. However, I quickly transitioned to datadriven solutions, focusing on Machine Learning and statistical methods. I am also passionate about developing personal projects, including short posts, video game development, and engaging in physical sports whenever possible.

## **Education**

**University of Girona** GIRONA, SPAIN

MSc. in Data Science 🗞

Sep. 2023

· Studies focused on advanced skills in analyzing and deriving insights from data using statistical and machine learning methods.

**University of Girona** GIRONA, SPAIN

BEng. in Computer Science ®

Jun. 2022

· I take pride in my accomplishment of attaining excellence in the final degree project, which entailed the creation of an open-source video game.

# Work Experience

**Citibeats** BARCELONA, SPAIN

Data Scientist Sep. 2023 - Mar. 2024

- · Conducted topic modeling pipelines, anomaly detection events with explainability to comprehend phenomena within time series, and clustering solutions for the identification of relevant groups.
- · Created private Python libraries, web-hook services, and deployed trained models in private
- · Provided technical support for previous company projects, i.e., fixing bugs, adding features, and re-fitting models.
- · Researched and implemented fast experiments, documenting the process for reproducibility and its results.
- · I was in charge of defining the working framework in the Data Science team, i.e., defining the tools for research, development and deployment.

**University of Girona** GIRONA, SPAIN

Associate Assistant Professor

Computer Vision Research

Feb. 2023 - Aug. 2023

Dec. 2022 - Aug. 2023

· My responsibilities included overseeing lab sessions in order to instruct students in functional and logic programming, correct lab projects, and supervise exams.

**Accenture SL** GIRONA, SPAIN

· Created and open source Computer-Aided Diagnosis platform for detecting Melanoma using Convolutional Neural Networks.

Nexus Geographics Girona, Spain

Data Engineer Sep. 2021 - Sep. 2022

 Significantly contributed to the development of a concurrent framework designed to capture, map, and store data from diverse sources.

- Created and manteined API micro-services to injest and serve data.
- Ensured data consistency across multiple databases.
- Designed and developed interactive web applications to visualize on-demand and streaming data.
- Provided training to new team members on the primary technologies utilized in the projects and offered problem-solving support.

NexTReTGIRONA, SPAINSoftware EngineerAbr. 2020 - Sep. 2021

• Designed and developed a wide range of Restful APIs.

Created interactive web applications for the healthcare sector, taking responsibility for building
modules including authentication, hospital bed administration, external hospital services, and
more.

# **Tech Skills**

**Programming Languages** Python, R, Haskell, Scala, Java, JS, C++, and more

ML & Data Tools PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, Hugging Face, Pandas, SQL, Kafka, and more

MLOps / DevOps MLFlow, W&B, Docker, GitHub Actions, and Git

**Frameworks** FastAPI, Flask, Spring Boot, Svelte, Angular, and more **Workflow** Jupyter Notebook, Neovim, Linux, GitHub and GitLab

**Cloud** AWS and Google Colab

# **Additional Skills of Interest**

**Languages** English (C1), Spanish (Native), Catalan (Bilingual)

Driver's License B

### Certificates

- 2023 Prevention & Emergency Management, Co-funded by the Erasmus+ Programme of the European Union
- 2022 Spark and Python for Big Data with PySpark, Udemy
- 2022 Advanced Machine Learning, Kaggle
- 2022 Advanced SQL, Kaggle
- 2021 Advanced Functional Programming (FP), University of Helsinki

#### References

PROF. DR. MATEU VILLARET 
PROFESSOR AT UNIVERSITY OF GIRONA
MATEU.VILLARET@UDG.EDU

PROF. DR. GUSTAVO PATOW PROFESSOR AT UNIVERSITY OF GIRONA GUSTAVO.PATOW@UDG.EDU QUIM DALMAU ®
TECH LEAD AT CITIBEATS
JDALMAUT@GMAIL.COM